A Guide to the Papers of Edmund S. Campbell
Special Collections Department, University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Papers of Edmund S. Campbell
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
3505
This collection consists of ca. 20,000 items.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
The papers were transfered to the Manuscripts Department from the School of Architecture's office files in July 1950.
Biographical/Historical Information
Edmund Schureman Campbell was born in New Jersey October 28, 1884. He received his B.S. (1906) and M.S. (1907) from the Massachusetts Institute of Technology, and spent the year 1911-1912 studying at l'Ecole des Beaux Arts, Paris. After serving on the faculty of Carnegie Institute of Technology, the Armour Institute of Technology, and as Dean of the Beaux Art Institute of Design in New York, he came to the University of Virginia in 1927 to head the School of Architecture and to be Curator of the Bayly Museum of Fine Arts. He held these positions until his death in 1950.
Scope and Content Information
The Edmund S. Campbell papers consist of ca. 20,000 items. They deal primarily with the University of Virginia's School of Architecture and related matters from 1919 to 1930. Much of the material relates to construction at the University, but also to various national architecture societies, institutes, and museums.
All Library folders include correspondence of University Librarian Harry Clemons. All University of Virginia Museum folders contain correspondence of University President John Lloyd Newcomb.
Arrangement
The collection is generally in the order derived by Professor Campbell- alphabetically by his topic headings. Within the folders, the order is chronological. Some four hundred unidentifiable items were placed at the end.
Contents List
- A Miscellaneous 1928-1949, ca. 150 items (Box 1)
- Adams, Mrs. Herbert 1946-1947, ca. 7 items (Box 1)
- Addresses (Old Students) 1937, 1 item (Box 1)
- Administrative Committees and Faculty 1939-1946, ca. 10 items (Box 1)
- Admitted Students 1946-1947, ca. 10 items (Box 1)
- Admitted Students and Information in Summer Quarter 1947-1948, ca. 20 items (Box 1)
- Advisory Committee of Architects 1928-1932, ca. 50 items (Box 1)
- A.I.A. (American Institute of Architects) 1941-1950, ca. 100 items (Box 1)
- Alabama Polytechnic Institute 1947, 1 item (Box 1)
- Albermarle Art League 1934-1939, ca. 50 items (Box 1)
- Albermarle Garden Club 1934-1949, ca. 50 items (Box 1)
  Includes letters from Harry Clemons
- Alderman Library 1933-1949, ca. 50 items (Box 1)
  Includes letters from John Lloyd Newcomb and Harry Clemons
- Alderman Portrait 1922-1923, ca. 15 items (Box 2)
- Alderman, Edwin Anderson 1927, 1 item (Box 2)
  See also: President's Office (Edwin Anderson Alderman)
- Alterations (Fayerweather) 1924-1925, ca. 25 items (Box 2)
- Alumni of the American Academy of Rome 1928-1937, ca. 20 items (Box 2)
- American Association of Museums 1935-1944, ca. 15 items (Box 2)
- American Federation of Arts 1935-1938, ca. 20 item (Box 2)
- American Institute of Architecture 1918-1945, ca. 25 items (Box 2)
- American Institute of Architects (Allied Arts) 1947-1948, 4 items (Box 2)
- American Institute of Architects (National Chapter) 1947-1949, ca. 25 items (Box 2)
- American Institute of Architects (National Educational Committee) 1947, ca. 15 items (Box 2)
- American Institute of Architects (Virginia Chapter) 1946-1947, ca. 50 items (Box 2)
- American Institute of Architects (Virginia Chapter) 1947-1948, ca. 50 items (Box 2)
- American Institute of Architects (Virginia Chapter) 1948-1949, ca. 20 items (Box 2)
- American Institute of Decorators 1931, 1 item (Box 2)
- Analytiques n.d., ca. 10 items (Box 2)
- Anderson, J.A. 1933-1949, ca. 10 items (Box 2)
- Anderson, L.B. 1931-1933, ca. 10 items (Box 2)
- Annual Reports 1935-1938, ca. 20 items (Box 2)
- Application for Degrees 1946, 1 item (Box 2)
- Application for Degrees 1948-1949, 3 items (Box 2)
- Application for degrees (field concentration) 1939, 1 item (Box 2)
- Applications for Positions 1926-1930, ca. 150 items (Box 2)
- Applications for Positions 1931-1939, ca. 200 items (Box 3)
- Applications for Positions 1940-1942, ca. 150 items (Box 3)
- Applications for Positions 1944-1945, 2 items (Box 3)
- Applications for Positions n.d., ca. 10 items (Box 3)
- Applications (Prospective Students) 1937-1944, ca. 10 items (Box 3)
- Appropriation Statements 1946-1947, ca. 10 items (Box 3)
- Architects Accrediting Board 1942, 4 items (Box 3)
- Architects Emergency Committee 1940, 2 items (Box 3)
- Architectural Association 1940-1942, ca. 10 items (Box 3)
- Architectural League of New York 1938-1948, ca. 20 items (Box 3)
- Architectural School (Exhibits) 1938, 5 items (Box 3)
- Architectural Registration 1942, 2 items (Box 3)
- Architectural School Modernizing n.d., 1 item (Box 3)
- Art Commission (Plans and Photographs) n.d., ca. 15 items (Box 4)
- Art Commission Law 1927-1933, ca. 10 items (Box 4)
- Art Dealers 1944-1945, 2 items (Box 4)
- Art Digest 1944, 1 item (Box 4)
- Art Index 1944, 3 items (Box 4)
- Art Lectures n.d., 1 item (Box 4)
- Artist in residence 1940, ca. 10 items (Box 4)
- Artist supplies 1928-1947, ca. 25 items (Box 4)
- Association of Collegiate Schools of Architucture 1919-1939, ca. 100 items (Box 4)
- Association of Collegiate Schools of Architecture 1921-1927, ca. 10 items (Box 4)
- Association of Collegiate Schools of Architecture 1928-1944, ca. 50 items (Box 4)
- Association of Collegiate Schools of Architecture (Miami) meeting 1946, ca. 10 items (Box 4)
- Association of Collegiate Schools of Architecture Report 1932, 1 item (Box 5)
- Association of Collegiate Schools of Architecture (Minutes) 1938-1945, ca. 25 items (Box 5)
- Association of the American Colleges 1941-1942, ca. 10 items (Box 5)
- Association of the Advancement of Architectural Education 1941, ca. 10 items (Box 5)
- Association of Schools n.d., 1 item (Box 5)
- B Miscellaneous 1935-1949, ca. 150 items (Box 5)
- B.A.I.D. (Beaux Arts Institute of Design) 1928-1929, 2 items (Box 5)
  see also: Beaux Arts
- B.A.I.D. (Beaux Arts Institute of Design) Correspondence 1925-1930, ca. 100 items (Box 5)
- B.A.I.D. (Beaux Arts Institute of Design) Correspondence 1940-1942, ca. 100 items (Box 6)
- B.A.I.D. (Beaux Arts Institute of Design) Correspondence 1942-1943, ca. 25 items (Box 6)
- B.A.I.D. (Beaux Arts Institute of Design) Judgements 1938-1947, ca. 10 items (Box 6)
- B.A.I.D. (Beaux Arts Institute of Design) Programs ca. 1920's and 1930's, ca. 25 items (Box 6)
- B.A.I.D. (Beaux Arts Institute of Design) Programs 1940's, ca. 25 items (Box 6)
- Baptist Church (Staunton) 1928-1937, ca. 20 items (Box 6)
- Baskerville and Son 1931-1935, ca. 15 items (Box 6)
- Beach, Chester 1931-1932, ca. 10 items (Box 6)
- Beaux Arts Institute of Design 1919-1922, ca. 10 items (Box 6)
- Beaux Arts Institute of Design 1926-1931, ca. 100 items (Box 6)
- Beaux Arts Institute of Design 1938-1940, ca. 100 items (Box 6)
- Beaux Arts Institute of Design 1946-1947, ca. 10 items (Box 7)
- Beaux Arts Institute of Design 1948, ca. 10 items (Box 7)
  see also B.A.I.D.
- Bell tower 1933, ca. 10 items (Box 7)
- Big Four and J.E. Massey (Painter) 1924-1930, ca. 15 items (Box 7)
- Bills 1928-1931, ca. 100 items (Box 7)
- Bills 1931-1932, ca. 15 items (Box 7)
- Bills 1933, ca. 10 items (Box 7)
- Bills 1934, ca. 10 items (Box 7)
- Bills 1935, ca. 20 items (Box 7)
- Bills 1936, ca. 50 items (Box 7)
- Bills 1938, ca. 25 items (Box 7)
- Bills 1938-1939, ca. 100 items (Box 7)
- Bills 1940, ca. 50 items (Box 8)
- Bills 1940-1941, ca. 75 items (Box 8)
- Bills 1941-1942, ca. 75 items (Box 8)
- Bills 1942-1943, ca. 75 items (Box 8)
- Bills 1942-1943, ca. 75 items (Box 8)
- Bills 1943-1944, ca. 10 items (Box 8)
- Binding (magazines, etc.) 1940-1942, ca. 25 items (Box 8)
- Blue Ridge Sanitarium 1933, 1 item (Box 8)
- Board of Architects 1928-1934, ca. 50 items (Box 8)
- Board of Architects 1928-1934, ca. 50 items (Box 8)
- Board of Architects (Data and Memoranda) ca. 1930, ca. 25 items (Box 8)
- Board of Architects (John K. Peeples) 1928-1930, ca. 20 items (Box 9)
- Board of Architects (President's Office) 1927-1929, ca. 10 items (Box 9)
- Board of Architects (from R.E. Lee Taylor) 1929-1930, ca. 40 letters (Box 9)
- Board of Architects (to R.E. Lee Taylor) 1930, ca. 10 letters (Box 9)
- Board of Architects (Blair, Walter, Dabney) 1928-1930, ca. 20 items (Box 9)
- Board of Registration n.d., ca. 20 items (Box 9)
- Books ordered 1919-1943, ca. 250 items, 6 folders (Box 10)
- Books Wanted 1920-1923, ca. 10 items (Box 10)
- Books (possibility of purchase) n.d., ca. 10 items (Box 10)
- Bottom, Davis 1930-1933, ca. 15 items (Box 10)
- Bradford, J.H. 1933, 2 items (Box 10)
- Bronz Dealers 1925-1936, ca. 15 items (Box 10)
- Bryan, John S. 1931, ca. 10 items (Box 10)
  see also William and Mary College (John S. Bryan)
- Budget (State Government) 1929, 2 items (Box 10)
- Building and Grounds 1945-1947, ca. 25 items (Box 10)
- Building and Remodeling at University of Virginia 1933-1950, ca. 10 items (Box 10)
- Bush-Brown, Professor Harry 1946-1947, 5 items (Box 10)
- Bursar (University of Virginia) 1945-1948, ca. 50 items (Box 10)
- Bursar's Office 1927-1929, ca. 25 items (Box 10)
- Bursar's Office 1928-1945, ca. 100 items (Box 10)
- Bursar (Mr. Carruthers) 1940-1945, ca. 15 items (Box 11)
  see also: Carruthers
- Bursar's Statements 1940's, ca. 10 items (Box 11)
- Burson, R.F. 1933, 6 items (Box 11)
- Byrd, Gov. Harry F. 1927-1930, ca. 20 items (Box 11)
- C Miscellaneous 1921-1947, ca. 150 items (Box 11)
- Calendars (terms) 1940-1942, ca. 10 items (Box 11)
- Camouflage 1943, 2 items (Box 11)
- Campbell, Edmund S. 1934-1939, ca. 100 items (Box 11)
- Campbell, Edmund S. 1940-1945, ca. 150 items (Box 12)
- Campbell, Edmund S. re: Dillard House 1940-1941, ca. 20 items (Box 12)
- Campbell, Edmund S. (Personal) 1934-1946, ca. 10 items (Box 12)
- Carruthers, E.I. (Bursar) 1938-1940, ca. 25 items (Box 12)
  see also: Bursar (Carruthers)
- Cary family, genealogy n.d., 1 item (Box 12)
- Cash Slips 1941-1942, ca. 25 items (Box 12)
- Catalogue 1945-1947, ca. 10 items (Box 12)
- Catalogue Information 1947-1948, ca. 10 items (Box 12)
- Catalogue (School of Art and Architecture) 1939-1941, ca. 25 items (Box 12)
- Catalogues (form letters to order same), ca. 20 items (Box 12)
- Catalogue (Permanent for Museum) n.d., ca. 15 items (Box 12)
- Centennial (University of Virginia) 1920-1921, ca. 20 items (Box 12)
- Chamber of Commerce 1932-1933, 4 items (Box 12)
- Changes in Courses 1939, ca. 20 items (Box 12)
- Cincinnati Society of New Jersey 1937, 2 items (Box 12)
- Catawba Sanitorium 1933 September 27, 1 item (Box 12)
- Central State Hospital 1933, 2 items (Box 12)
- Clark, Adele 1931, 4 items (Box 12)
- Clark, Eliot 1939, 2 items (Box 12)
- Clemons, Harry 1939-1940, ca. 100 items (Box 12)
- Clemons, Harry 1941-1942, ca. 50 items (Box 12)
- Cleveland School of Architecture 1933, 2 items (Box 13)
- Clipping Bureaus 1935-1936, ca. 10 items (Box 13)
- College Art Association of America 1933-1942, ca. 75 items (Box 13)
- College Committee n.d., 1 item (Box 13)
- College Exhibits 1939, 2 items (Box 13)
- College Topics 1935-1938, ca. 10 items (Box 13)
- Colleges and Universities 1945-1946, 2 items (Box 13)
- Collins, T.J. and Sons, Architects 1930, 4 items (Box 13)
- Color Theory 1926-1927, 1 item (Box 13)
- Columbia University School of Architecture 1946, ca. 10 items (Box 13)
- Columbia University (L.C. Dillenback) 1934-1935, 4 items (Box 13)
- Committee on Conservation of Cultural Resources 1941-1942, 2 items (Box 13)
- Committee- Reunification of American Institute of Architects and State Societies 1942, 4 items (Box 13)
- Competitions 1942, 4 items (Box 13)
- Concerts 1919-1920, ca. 100 items (Box 13)
- Concerts (Harold Bauer) 1919-1920, ca. 10 items (Box 13)
- Concerts (Cincinnati Symphony) 1919, ca. 10 items (Box 13)
- Concerts (General) 1919-1920, ca. 75 items (Box 13)
- Concerts (Freida Hemple) n.d., ca. 20 items (Box 13)
  Concert folders include many of Fiske Kimball letters
- Construction Clippings- dams, etc. n.d., ca. 10 items (Box 13)
- Contemporary American Art 1921, ca. 25 items (Box 13)
- Conventions, Conferences, etc. 1942, 4 items (Box 13)
- Copies; Quizzes and Exams n.d., ca. 15 items (Box 13)
- Corneal, Johnson and Wright 1930-1935, ca. 50 items (Box 14)
- Correspondence (General) 1929-1935, ca. 20 items (Box 14)
- Correspondence (Professor Campbell) 1939-1944 (Box 14)
  Includes correspondence from President John Lloyd Newcomb, Fiske Kimball and Harry Clemons
- Couses 1927-1930, ca. 20 items (Box 14)
- Courses (special) 1931-1934, ca. 10 items (Box 14)
- Court House (Yorktown, Va) 1946-1947, ca. 20 items (Box 14)
- Courts (Squash and handball) 1937-1938, ca. 20 items (Box 14)
- Cox, Allyn 1930-1934, ca. 30 items (Box 14)
  Includes correspondence with John Lloyd Newcomb
- D Correspondence 1928-1949, ca. 50 items (Box 14)
- Darden, Colgate W. 1949-1950, ca. 10 items (Box 14)
- Darrow, Clarence 1932-1933, ca. 10 items (Box 14)
- Data for Programs n.d., 3 items (Box 14)
- Data (perspective) n.d., 4 items (Box 14)
- Dean of the College (George Ferguson) 1937-1938, ca. 25 items (Box 14)
- Dean of the College of Arts and Sciences (George Ferguson) 1940-1942, ca. 25 items (Box 14)
  See also: Ferguson, Dean
- Dean of the Graduate School (John Metcalf) 1932-1936, ca. 10 items (Box 14)
- Dean's Office (Correspondence) 1927-1930, ca. 100 items (Box 14)
  Includes correspondence with Edwin Anderson Alderman and John Lloyd Newcomb
- Dean Page 1930-1931, ca. 20 items (Box 14)
- Dean of University (I.M. Lewis) 1934-1937, 2 items (Box 14)
- Descriptive Geometry (Correspondence re:) 1937, ca. 10 items (Box 15)
- Desk Copies to the Field 1936-1944, ca. 30 items (Box 15)
- Dettor, J.L. (Charlottesville) 1934-1937, ca. 10 items (Box 15)
- Dillard, James Hardy 1930-1931, ca. 10 items (Box 15)
- Discussions of Art Commission ca. 1930's (Box 15)
- Dodson, E. Griffith 1935, 3 items (Box 15)
- Du Pont Teaching Fellowship 1940-1941, ca. 10 items (Box 15)
- E Miscellaneous 1934-1943, ca. 25 items (Box 15)
- Easels, (Anderson) n.d., 3 items (Box 15)
- Eastern State Hospital 1932-1933, 3 items (Box 15)
- Emerson, Prof. William 1927-1938, ca. 100 items (Box 15)
- Engineering Building (specifications) n.d. (Box 15)
- Engineering Building 1934, ca. 50 items (Box 15)
- Engineers' and Architects' Registration Act 1921-1922, 4 items (Box 15)
- Entrance Inquiries 1939-1942, ca. 50 items (Box 15)
- Equipment Lists n.d., 5 items (Box 15)
- Equipment (School) 1930-1938, ca. 75 items (Box 15)
- Evans, Rudolph (sculptor) 1930-1931, ca. 15 items (Box 16)
- Eubank and Caldwell, Architects 1930-1934, ca. 15 items (Box 16)
- Examinations n.d. and 1921, ca. 25 items (Box 16)
- Examinations 1930's-1943, ca. 35 items (Box 16)
- Exhibitions (School) 1928-1935, ca. 25 items (Box 16)
- Exhibitions (temporary) 1940-1942, ca. 75 items (Box 16)
- Exhibitions (varied) 1919-1921, ca. 200 items (Box 16)
- Exhibits (Association Collegiate School of Architecture) 1941-1942, ca. 20 items (Box 16)
- Exhibits (school) 1942, 5 items (Box 16)
- Exhibits (temporary museum) 1940-1943, ca. 100 items (Box 16)
  Includes a letter from James Southall Wilson, 1942 September 9
- Exhibits (traveling) 1941, 3 items (Box 16)
- Expenses (Correspondence and vouchers) 1928-1930, ca. 50 items (Box 17)
- Extension Division 1927-1938, ca. 70 items (Box 17)
- Extension Division 1944, 4 items (Box 17)
- Extension Division (Zehmer and Rorer) 1936-1940, ca. 20 items (Box 17)
- F Miscellaneous 1930-1945, ca. 125 items (Box 17)
- Faculty (Departmental) 1938-1940, ca. 50 items (Box 17)
- Faculty (Departmental) 1939-1943, ca. 50 items (Box 17)
- Faculty (University of Virginia) 1929-1937, ca. 50 items (Box 17)
- Faculty (New Architecture Members) 1938, ca. 75 items (Box 17)
  Includes Fiske Kimball Correspondence
- Failures among Students in Virginia Universities 1926-1930, 4 items (Box 17)
- Farmington 1928-1930, ca. 50 items (Box 18)
- Farmington Country Club 1928-1930, ca. 125 items (Box 18)
- Fayerweather Hall (Fine Arts Library) 1936-1938, ca. 20 items (Box 18)
- Federal Building (Richmond) 1929, 6 items (Box 18)
  Includes letter from Harry Boyd
- Ferguson, Dean 1938-1945, ca. 50 items (Box 18)
  see also: Dean Ferguson
- Fire Prevention 1921-1923, ca. 20 items (Box 18)
- Fontanebleau School of Fine Arts 1932-1938 (Box 18)
- Foreign Universities 1928, ca. 10 items (Box 18)
- Fountain (drinking) 1937-1939, ca. 25 items (Box 18)
- Frishmuth, Harriet W. 1931, ca. 25 items (Box 18)
- Frye and Stone, Architects 1930-1934, ca. 25 items (Box 18)
- Furniture (New Law building) 1931-1932, ca. 30 items (Box 18)
- G Miscellaneous 1929-1950, ca. 150 items (Box 18)
- Garden Club 1944, 2 items (Box 18)
- General 1929-1931, ca. 20 items (Box 18)
- General Commission Letters 1930-1935, ca. 100 items (Box 19)
  Includes letters from John Garland Pollard and Philip Stern
- Gifts 1917-1938, ca. 100 items (Box 19)
- Gilbert, Ernest R. 1944, 5 items (Box 19)
- Goodwin, Dr. W.A.R. 1934, 5 items (Box 19)
- Governor's Mansion 1932, 5 items (Box 19)
  Includes letters from J.G. Pollard
- Grounds 1932 December 19, 3 items (Box 19)
- Grades 1931-1932, ca. 50 items (Box 19)
- Grades 1932-1933, ca. 25 items (Box 19)
- Grades 1933-1934, ca. 25 items (Box 19)
- Grades 1934-1935, ca. 25 items (Box 19)
- Grades 1935-1936, ca. 25 items (Box 19)
- Grades 1936-1937, ca. 25 items (Box 19)
- Grades 1937-1938, ca. 25 items (Box 19)
- Grades 1938-1939, ca. 25 items (Box 20)
- Grades 1938-1939, ca. 25 items (Box 20)
- Grades 1939-1940, ca. 25 items (Box 20)
- Grades 1939 (first term), ca. 25 items (Box 20)
- Grades 1939-1940, ca. 25 items (Box 20)
- Grades 1940-1941, ca. 25 items (Box 20)
- Grades 1940-1941, ca. 25 items (Box 20)
- Grades 1942-1943, ca. 25 items (Box 20)
- Grades 1942-1943, ca. 25 items (Box 20)
- H Miscellaneous 1931-1944, ca. 150 items (Box 20)
- Hammond, Lews M. 1939, 3 items (Box 20)
- Handbook (Professional) 1941, 4 items (Box 20)
- Hansen, Oscar M. 1931, ca. 10 items (Box 20)
- Hansen, C.H. and Co. 1937-1938, ca. 20 items (Box 20)
- Hartman, Frank E. (Buildings and Grounds) 1933-1944, ca. 50 items (Box 20)
- Hayes, John G. (Williams, Mullins, Hazelgrove Law Firms) 1940-1941, 4 items (Box 20)
- Helburn, William, Publisher 1928-1944, ca. 100 items (Box 21)
- Holland, Dr. Leicester B. 1933-1936, ca. 50 items (Box 21)
- Housing n.d., 1 item (Box 21)
- Huntington, William E. 1940-1942, ca. 25 items (Box 21)
- I Miscellaneous 1933-1941, ca. 15 items (Box 21)
- Illinois, University of, Registration System 1919, 1 item (Box 21)
- Index-Grand Prix et Concours n.d., ca. 10 items (Box 21)
- Instructions (Departmental) 1933-1937, ca. 50 items (Box 21)
- Instructors in Art and Architecture 1927-1930, ca. 10 items (Box 21)
- Instructors (Departmental) 1931-1932, 6 items (Box 21)
- Insurance (University) 1933-1937, 6 items (Box 21)
- Interiors 1944, 5 items (Box 21)
- J Miscellaneous 1933-1944, ca. 25 items (Box 21)
- Jansen, J.H. 1928-1945, ca. 20 items (Box 21)
- Jefferson- 200th Anniversary 1936-1941, ca. 15 items (Box 21)
- Jefferson Memorial Foundation 1941-1942, ca. 25 items (Box 21)
  Contains correspondence of Fiske Kimball
- Johns, Jay Winston 1931-1949, ca. 20 items (Box 21)
- Johnson and Brannan, Architects 1930-1946, ca. 20 items (Box 21)
- Johnston Bust 1932-1934, ca. 50 items (Box 21)
  Includes correspondence of Pollard
- K Miscellaneous 1921-1947, ca. 100 items (Box 22)
- Keck, Charles 1930-1937, ca. 50 items (Box 22)
- Kendall, William S. 1938, ca. 15 items (Box 22)
- Kimball, Fiske 1928-1946, ca. 50 items (Box 22)
  Includes letters to Pollard
- Kocher, A. Lawrence 1927-1928, ca. 50 items (Box 22)
- Kreisler, Fritz 1919, ca. 20 items (Box 22)
- L Miscellaneous 1927-1949, ca. 100 items (Box 22)
- Lane (Ann Maria), Tablet 1933, ca. 15 items (Box 22)
- Lantern Slides 1919-1922, ca. 50 items (Box 22)
  see also: Slides (lantern)
- Landscape Architecture 1931-1937, ca. 50 items (Box 22)
  Includes correspondence from President John Lloyd Newcomb
- Landscape Garden Society 1935-1936, ca. 20 items (Box 22)
- Landscape Schools 1939, 1 item (Box 22)
- LaRowe Bust 1944, 1 item (Box 22)
- Leavens, William, Inc. (furniture) 1927-1936, ca. 20 items (Box 22)
- Lectures 1930-1938, ca. 25 items (Box 22)
- Lectures 1938-1939, ca. 25 items (Box 23)
- Lectures 1940-1942, ca. 25 items (Box 23)
- Lectures (given) 1934-1936, ca. 25 items (Box 23)
- Lee, Robert E. (Statue) 1928-1936 (Box 23)
  Includes Harry Byrd and Pollard correspondence
- Letcher, Greenlee D. 1930-1933, ca. 10 items (Box 23)
- Library (general file) 1939, ca. 20 items (Box 23)
- Library (correspondence) 1927-1930, ca. 100 items (Box 23)
- Library (correspondence) 1931-1932, ca. 75 items (Box 23)
- Library (correspondence) 1933-1934, ca. 150 items (Box 23)
- Library (correspondence) 1935-1938, ca. 150 items (Box 23)
- Library fines 1938-1939, ca. 10 items (Box 23)
- Library fines 1940-1942, ca. 20 items (Box 23)
- Library (Instructions and regulations) 1930-1938, ca. 200 items (Box 24)
- Library (Notices) 1930-1938, ca. 200 items (Box 24)
- Library (Ryan collection) 1937-1938, ca. 10 items (Box 24)
  All Library Folders Include Correspondence of Harry Clemons
- Life Magazine 1942-1943, 1 item (Box 24)
- List of material loaned n.d., 1 item (Box 24)
- Lists of Students 1940, 1 item (Box 24)
- Log Houses 1932-1933, ca. 10 items (Box 24)
- Long, Raymond V. 1934, 4 items (Box 24)
- Lorentzen, Floyd E. 1935, 3 items (Box 24)
- Lynch, Kenneth, Inc. 1936-1937, 3 items (Box 24)
- M Miscellaneous 1928-1943, ca. 200 items (Box 24)
- Mc Miscellaneous 1935-1945, ca. 50 items (Box 24)
- McCaughney, W.F. 1936-1938, ca. 15 items (Box 24)
- McGuire Monument 1933-1934, ca. 20 items (Box 24)
- McGuffey, William Holmes 1935, ca. 15 items (Box 24)
  Includes letters of President John Lloyd Newcomb
- McIntire Portrait 1922, 5 items (Box 25)
  Includes letter to Fiske Kimball
- Magazines (binding, etc.) 1942-1943, 5 items (Box 25)
- Magazines (old) n.d., 1 item (Box 25)
- Magazine subscriptions 1939-1940, ca. 20 items (Box 25)
- Makielski, Stanislaw J. 1919-1938, ca. 100 items (Box 25)
- Maphis, Dean Charles G. 1930-1937, ca. 15 items (Box 25)
- Marble 1935, 2 items (Box 25)
- Marble Dealers 1931, 1 item (Box 25)
- Massachusetts Institute of Technology 1929, 1 item (Box 25)
- Maury Bust 1929-1933, ca. 10 items (Box 25)
- Medical College of Virginia 1929-1933, ca. 10 items (Box 25)
  Includes letter of Harry F. Byrd
- Medical School- McIntire Addition 1933, 2 items (Box 25)
- Melchers, Gari 1930-1933, ca. 25 items (Box 25)
- Melchers, Mrs. Gari 1933-1936, ca. 25 items (Box 25)
- Memoranda 1929-1933, ca. 50 items (Box 26)
- Memorial Gates 1928-1930, ca. 20 items (Box 25)
- Memorials, Tablets, etc. 1920-1930, ca. 30 items (Box 25)
- Modeling (class and materials) 1934-1935, ca. 50 items (Box 25)
- Modeling Equipment 1939, ca. 10 items (Box 25)
- Modeling Materials and Tools 1932-1933, ca. 10 items (Box 25)
- Models for Life 1939, ca. 10 items (Box 25)
- Models- time sheet n.d., 1 item (Box 25)
- Moeller, Otto 1935-1936, ca. 10 items (Box 25)
- Monmouth Historical Society 1935, 3 items (Box 25)
- Monument (Houdon Statue) 1931-1934, ca. 10 items (Box 25)
- Monuments 1919-1937, ca. 50 items (Box 25)
- Munford, Mary B. 1930-1931, ca. 10 items (Box 26)
- Municipal Art Committee 1936, ca. 10 items (Box 26)
- Mural Competition for Courtroom 1935, 3 items (Box 26)
- Murals in Clark Memorial Hall 1938, ca. 10 items (Box 26)
- Murphy, Fred V. 1928-1938, ca. 20 items (Box 26)
- Museum (attendance) ca. 1934, ca. 10 items (Box 26)
- Museum Competition 1932, ca. 20 items (Box 26)
  Includes John G. Pollard letter
- Museum Equipment 1933-1937, ca. 75 letters (Box 26)